Okay. I just wanted to read this to y'all because I think it's always funny. I know
some of y'all are artists and you be thinking like, what's the point? What am I doing? What's
this all about? But make sure that you keep your shit. All right. Make sure that you keep your
shit. Okay. Because hold on, let me block this person real quick because I just found all these
raps and I'm going to use one of them in my show. Hey Finland. And so I wrote this. Okay. I wrote this
in 2003. I wrote this in 2003. Okay. I wrote this in 2003. I thought I blocked this person.
Get this person fucking out of here. Okay. First of all, I wrote, sometimes I look at fame and wonder
if I want it. Seems like so many people are fiending for stardom, but don't know how to act once they got
it. The industry can be a weird place to be careful not to lose yourself in the, in the sands of
celebrity. This is from 2003. All right. Now this is from 2003. Now let me see. Now listen to how this
sounds in 2025. I won't deny it. I'm a real writer, but they want to censor me. I got a problem with
the FCC because they trying to take our liberty. So I won't deny it. We're under fire. Residents of this
country. These days, we ain't got free speech. This ain't no democracy. And my ambitions as a writer,
lyricist, thinker, and one who expresses through scripted gifts are slowly being killed by the recent
shift of government involvement in solving the so-called problem of America's airways and TV
screens being overrun with debauchery. All it took was a glimpse of Janet's mammary. This is right.
For the government to kick in the door like B.I.G. inside smothering our opinions with American flags,
roping up reality talk, leaving free speech gagged. It's sad, but true. I'm moving in reverse.
Got original thought in the pine box and Colin Powell's son is driving the hearse.
If shit gets worse, you about to see every poet and MC walking around with a tattoo on their neck
that reads parental advisory because I won't deny it. I don't give a damn. I say what I want and speak
from the heart. I live my life the same way I share this art with passion and intensity. Censoring my
verbosity is like taking drums away from the slaves of my ancestry. Deaden their communication and ability
to share their thoughts on how to get free. My voice is my rhythm to awaken my community. That's why
they muffling our mics to try to stop the unity, using purity as an excuse to widen the watchful eye.
First, it was McCarthy, then COINTELPRO, now the Patriot laws, and I won't deny it.
I think it's crazy that the powers that be want to act like the last straw was Miss Jackson being
nested or blaming on the downward spiral of this country's piety. But nobody seems to address or
have a problem with the lies that every day are spilled from the twixt politician's lips.
Yeah, they want to censor forward a little words in honesty, yet no one fined the presidency for lying
to the entire country. Because them figures got they thug game right. Stolen the election, now they
taking our rights. I'm scared of what I see. Because I know that a new battle is brewing beneath our feet.
I wrote this in 2000. What year was Janet's titty come out? What year was that? What year was the
Janet Jackson Super Bowl scandal? 04. I wrote this in 04. I wrote this in 04. I said,
I'm scared of what I see. Because I know that a new battle is brewing beneath our feet.
And it's only a matter of time before history repeats itself, as it will inevitably.
And instead of paying fines for speaking our minds, like Malcolm, they'll start making us pay with
our mortality. That's wild. Let's see. February 1st, 04. I was 21. That's crazy, bro. That's crazy.
So to all my poets, keep writing. And keep your stuff. Keep your work. Because you don't know when
you're going to come back to it. And you don't... Man, and sometimes it's like, it ends up being
prophetic in ways that you didn't even imagine. This is all rhymes. This is all rhymes. Rhymes and my...
This is rhymes and notes from class. And it's just wild to just see. Like, I literally have...
It's literally a rap. And then the next page is outline of Gwendolyn Brooks and Audre Lorde paper.
How important were the artistic expressions to the success of the movement?
This is about South Africa. I'm writing here about South Africa and apartheid.
Look at this rap. Look at the first line of this rap.
Proven profit. My future, I predict it written. Move and watch it. The signs on my path from the
beginning. Never bling bling and always thinking, writing and spitting. Deconstructing the system,
the kinks I be revealing. Dealing, fertilizing minds through poetry and rhymes. Bringing truth to
fools who's lost and confused. Focus locusts. Plagues nor eclipses. Contriptus. Still act.
Contriptus. Stellar soul. Universal rapstress. Use lyrics to uplift. Motivate. Elevate.
My vocals take the put asunder. Make them levitate. Some sweat and salivate
over this magistrate. Diva queen. My crown's a Kangol. Trust my reign will be great.
Race is about power and beyond identity. Placed in existence by those who sought superiority.
I'm lighter than you and you're darker than me. That to them meant inferiority. History
applauds the past and forefathers who pillaged indigenous villages, raped women, and rejected
their sons and daughters. This is dated September 24th. No, sorry. July 24th, 2003. That's when
this is dated. I don't know right now. I have this moment on here. I'm having a full circle
moment and I don't know what the spiritual, I don't know what the spiritual significance
of that is, but I've literally made a full circle in my life and I came back. It's like
I left and came back to myself. Okay, listen. I said, history applauds the past and forefathers
who pillaged indigenous villages, raped women, and rejected their sons and daughters. Those
imperialists. It's like I'm living a second life in my life. I got to think on this one.
Those imperialists who took trips around the globe. I didn't even realize that I knew what
imperialists were in 2003. Those imperialists who took trips around the globe to oust others
of another color out of their rightful homes, all in the race to claim ownership of power.
They scoured the earth, found civilizations and tribesmen. Then they broke them down, bartering
freedom. Hello. Wait, by the way, someone said you're the fourth member of X-Clan. To the east,
my brother, to the east, to the east, my brother, to the east. Then they broke them down,
bartering freedom, offering gold and jewels, things of that like, all the while feeding false
truths and clouded insight. They eradicated anyone who lifted their voice to fight, assumed because
they had ships and royal blessings that divinely they were right. So practically overnight,
they erected a system based on income and devoid of wisdom from kingdoms to presidencies.
They crossed the seven seas and wrote laws and decrees till the power couldn't be ceased.
Now the same who started it are at the finish line, holding the gun, laughing in the sun,
screaming at the top of their lungs, run, donkey, run. We're the black, brown, Indian,
and Asian. We're the only ones taking part in the race. And though I'm proud of my medium shaded skin,
I wasn't labeled black till whites judged that there was nothing within, but the competition
ain't about who's gonna win. That's the truth. Only a few know. And it's a shame because victory
will only come when we learn. Oh, that's the truth. But only a few know when it's a shame
because victory will only come when we learn. It's not a game. Oh no, this would be very easy
to remember on stage. Anything that rhymes is easy to remember. And then look at this little
side thing I wrote over here. People think life is about competition. Who can have the most this and
that, but we are all different and cannot compete against each other. I mean, I'm just, I'm just,
I'm just fascinated because I feel like I'm reading the words of somebody else. You want to hear one more?
Let me know. If not, I'll go away. Okay. Here's another one. Well, you just said red, black,
red, black, and green. Here's a short one. Listen to this. These words come from gumboots and reggae
roots, broken dreams and broken spirits, hardened heels and elbows, dashikis and shell toes, red, black,
and green, soul pics and afro sheen, empty pockets and ones bursting at the seams. These lines aren't
refined or perfected. All I hope for you to see when you dissect them is the depths of their nature
and the devotion to the voices that came before them. Cause anything before 93 is whack to me.
I've heard from far too many cats and multi-platinum MCs rhyming in a prime, but yet to align with
their blueprint. Cause even before they knew ink, cats was past the brink of reaching to another level,
getting known as rhyming rebels, kicking up dust so that we never have to settle. Yet today's MC forgot
to watch the episode before the industry preempted programming of their identities. We're the sequel
of a legacy of all those before the pros that rose above negativity and that laid words on pages and
spit vocals on stages. So I could even be an MC. This here is my toast to all of those who refuse to
go quietly and said, I'll be damned if they get the best of me teaching me how to craft artillery from
this poetry and battle the system with this lyrical artistry. And this is the last one. They say the world
is run by the rich, but I say it's powered by the hungry. This whole time, I gotta send this to Claudia.
I was a Marxist this whole time. Like, this is why you gotta write journals. This is why you gotta like
put shit down because there's really something happening within me cellularly right now. Like realizing
that I was on this when I was 21. Like, I don't know. I gotta really sit with this later, but this is like
bugging me out. Like, how on this I was. How on this I was. They say the world is run by the rich,
but I say it's powered by the hungry. Those whose motivation is being the next success story.
Those whose grind keeps the industry in motion. Whose lives are rooted in ambition and devotion.
But those on top oftentimes don't recognize this notion. They too busy being fabulous and gloating.
Surrounded by yes men and women who tell them they're the best. Flossing their jewelry and never
giving their smile a rest. Walking through crowds of wannabe stars who hold that dream near and dear to
their hearts. Those who are still in love with the art and haven't let the money tear our souls apart
See heads is cool at the start. Just stepping off the ground as we witness them taste success for the
first time. But so often that transforms into a beast of the worst kind. Where heads fall in love
with themselves and damn near lose their minds. To the bullshit of the industry. The phoniness and
fakeness. Only thing still real is the diamonds on their wrists. Everybody's shiny and happy.
Pleasing the fans and posing for paparazzi. But so many are so lost in the glitz and the glam that they
become blind to the reality of who they are and forget the point at which they began.
And the hook is make them pay. Make them pay. Make them pay. Make them pay.
Everybody had to pay dues. It's just the way it goes. Whether it's fetching someone's coffee or
doing bullshit shows. Where there's 20 people in the crowd and 10 of your friends. And you feel bad
because they've heard the same piece over and over again. Whether it's answering phones or working two
and three jobs. Just to save up money every month to pay the note on your car. Because you're still
living with moms making beats in their basement. And if you moved out you'd have to sell your
equipment to pay rent. Whether it's handing out flyers or waiting outside the club. Because you
told the bounce of your name and you were completely snubbed. Then he moved you aside and said go to the
end of the line. When you asked why he said because you're nobody quit wasting my time. Whether it's
walking to Juniors for cheesecake or DJing facing the wall. With the mic held together with scotch tape and
crowd down the hall. After carrying your crates in by yourself and out by yourself too. Because
you knew the promoter were in front of your dough. And you didn't. Because you knew the promoter.
Ah! After carrying your crates in and out by yourself too. Because the promoter were in front
of your dough. So you couldn't pay a crew. When you get to the top rung on the ladder to success.
A lot of people seem so easily to forget what they went through to get there. And how many are going
through it every day. Keeping track of everyone and everywhere who got them played. Saying to
themselves one day I'ma make them pay. Make them pay. Make them pay. Everybody who doubted who hated
who should wait. Make them pay. Make them pay. Everybody who doubted who hated said I'd never make
it. Make them pay. Make them pay. Everybody who fronted who faked who stunted in my face. I make them pay.
Make them pay. Then I have one last verse. You best believe there's always someone like me
waiting in the wings. Who's grown up watching and perfecting how to win. Who knows the benefits of
hard work and dedication. Whose patience will only last so long amidst the waiting. Who takes it
personal every time someone questions our position and uses it to fuel our movement with motivation.
who doesn't rely on shadiness or vengeance. Just personal improvement to the as the best form
of retaliation because the earth is round. Everything you do comes back to you and karma is a bitch.
So I'm careful of what I do. I have no problem paying dues but when it comes time to profit
all y'all who forgot yourselves feeling so important looking down on all of us little people thinking
we'd stay dormant careful because your feeble frames will soon be storming coming through with nothing
but the truth and strength and will to make it to the top and make room for coming through with nothing
but the truth and strength and will to make it to the top and make room to come and build. This is
for all my people on the grind. Keep on till you're satisfied and for all who thought we were worthless
forgetting what we have inside just know that in due time you're gonna feel it when we make them pay make
We make them pay, make them pay, make them pay, make them pay, make them pay, make them pay, make them pay, make them pay.
Everybody who doubted, who hated, who said I'd never make it, make them pay, make them pay.
Everybody who doubted, who said I'd never make it, make them pay, make them pay.
Everybody who fronted and tried to play all in my face, I'd make them pay, make them pay.
My mic name was Amanda Diva.
I got a whole album here.
And just to take it to another level for y'all,
2001 hip hop back to school folder.
And this, this is all rhymes.
This is all rhymes.
All of this, all of this is raps.
Hey Eric, all of this is raps.
Do you see this?
So when people like meet you at phases in your life
and they act like you just like showed up,
like you just fell out the sky,
you'd be like, look at the date on this.
Look at the date.
Look at the date on that.
It's 2025.
Eyes open, but not seeing where I'm going.
Walking my steps ain't showing imprints I'm knowing.
Little of my future these days.
Everybody says you'll be a star.
Famous, the people will speak your name.
But as my pen moves across these lines,
one thing remains.
Game ain't on my mind.
I'm defined by artistry.
Cause dollar signs and creativity feel like hypocrisy.
But I got to eat and thrive and live successfully.
Sometimes the bullshit gets to me.
I must undergo inventory of my soul.
My goal to leave this earth with more than a memory,
to take a place in history for people to remember me.
Gets heavy like I'm Atlas with the world on my shoulders.
Thinking how can I be bolder?
Evade my spark becoming a smolder.
Amanda, of smiles and laughs.
My complex brain ingrained with fears on how to maintain.
And doubts on what I've laid down on paper, on my skill,
on my power, on my flow.
Claiming lyrical prowess, but not always believing it is so.
How can I expect heads to feel me if I don't feel myself?
Confidence is relevant.
Self-assurance is the best type of wealth.
I'm a diva by name and identity every day of the week.
Need to see what others see do.
Need to see what others see.
Do what truly makes me happy.
Spit with witty words and gleams of vivid vocabulary.
If you're gonna rhyme,
spit cause life depends on your words and delivery.
Rain sleet of snow, I must move blow by blow.
Get my weight and grow.
Ascend in my river to flow.
And extends like the fingers grasping my pen
to deltas of clarity.
I stay asking questions,
but the answers all lie within me.
How old was I in 2001?
I must have been 20?
Yeah, I was 20.
Damn.
My little heart.
My little heart, man.
I don't know why reading that.
Well, I do know why reading that.
When you read,
when you read,
when you read like your,
your, your,
your words that are really honest
from your days of insecurity
or from coming from
like bad relationships
and like learning,
it feels like such a big deal
to get to the other side of that.
But I'm just like,
damn, I was 20
and I was like really tapped in.
I was really tapped in.
I mean,
this is a whole poem called freedom.
Thank you guys.
I've been getting a lot of compliments
on this green today.
Green really is my color though.
So that doesn't surprise me.
Common misplacements of statements
referring to this member
of the female gender.
It's so,
it's so obvious
that I'm a 90s kid,
that I'm an 80s baby,
like the way that I rhyme.
Common misplacements of statements
referring to this member
of the female gender.
Bitch don't describe me
and chicken head don't either.
Newbie and horizon.
Shine on truth on lies.
This is the real speak.
What I feel like,
I might as well be the fourth member
of Diggable Planets.
Why?
I mean,
I wake up to,
I wake up to blowout comb.
I listen to blowout comb
like once a month.
Oh yes,
very nerdy to print it out.
And then in here,
I have lyrics
to it ain't hard to tell.
Life's a bitch.
Thieves in the night.
Last Emperor,
Secret Wars.
Anywho,
I came in,
I started doing this
because I'm working
on a piece right now
and I wanted to put
a little wrap in it.
Not I break from the roll,
I break from the mold
like recess in elementary.
Anywho,
thank y'all for indulging,
indulging me
in my little,
in my little
trek through.
and then track down
memory lane.
Hold on to that folder.
Baby,
I had this folder
since 2001.
One thing you can say
about me is
I am a hoarder.
I hope y'all enjoyed that
as much as I did.
People always say
life is short
and I don't say that.
I say life is long
because
when you do something
that you regret,
it stays with you
all the time.
When you don't do something
that you regret not doing,
it stays with you
all the time.
so you don't do it
because
life is short
and you may not get
the opportunity
to do it again.
You do it
or you don't do it
because life is long
and you do not
want it to be
taking up space
that you could use
for
existing in new spaces,
for expanding.
So that's
that's my philosophy.
But you guys
have a
have a fabulous
rest of your afternoon.
This was very random.